Preliminary Guide to the Robert Fowler Underground Comics Collection M2090
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Robert Fowler underground comics collection
1968-2004
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
M2090
5.5 Linear Feet (3 manuscript boxes and 1 flat box)
Comic books are in mixed condition, with some ink transfer. They are not housed in folders or plastic sleeves.
Preliminary set of 21 selected titles processed and made available; the entire collection consists of approximately 3966 underground comic books, most in regular or magazine size, with a few oversize, tabloids, minicomics, and digest sized publications. Represented in the collection are thousands of authors. Roughly two-thirds of the collection is single issue comics, with the other third made up of multi-issue series. Topics reflected include politics, sexuality, hippies, classical themes including fantasy or science fiction, and factual topics like biography or history.
Content Description
21 titles in this collection have been processed and are listed here arranged by title and date; the remainder is closed until processed.
Biographical / Historical
Robert Fowler grew up in Los Altos, California and began collecting comics while at the Claremont Colleges (1966-1970), beginning with Zap Comix and the Young Lust series. Fowler started keeping a database of his comics collection between 1977-1980 while working as a computer programmer at Byte Shop #12 in Pasadena. He collected most of his comics between 1980 and 1998, though he continued to collect until 2014.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Robert Fowler, 2014.
Conditions Governing Access
Preliminary set of selected titles is open for research; remainder are closed until processed.
Comic books, strips, etc. -- Periodicals.; Underground comic books, strips, etc.
- Bijou Funnies, numbers 2, 3, and 5, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bijou Funnies, numbers 6-8, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bizarre Sex numbers 1-2 (two different issues numbered 2), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bizarre Sex numbers 3-5, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bizarre Sex number 5 (large format), 1976 (Flat-boxes 4, Folder 1)
- Bizarre Sex number 6 (large format), 1977 (Flat-boxes 4, Folder 2)
- Bizarre Sex numbers 7-10, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Come out Comix (single issue), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Corporate Crime Comics numbers 1-2, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Dynamite Damsels (single issue), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Eightball numbers 1-3, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Eightball numbers 4-6, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Eightball numbers 7-9, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Eightball numbers 10-12, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Eightball numbers 13-15, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Eightball numbers 16-18, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Eightball numbers 19-20, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Eightball numbers 21-22, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Eightball number 23 (large format), 2004 (Flat-boxes 4, Folder 3)
- Fabulous Furry Freak Brothers numbers 1-3 (two issues of number 1; one in German), 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Fabulous Furry Freak Brothers numbers 4-7, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Fabulous Furry Freak Brothers numbers 8-10, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Fabulous Furry Freak Brothers numbers 11-13, 1990-1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Feds 'n Heads Comics, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Gay Comix numbers 1-4, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Gay Comix numbers 5-8, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Gay Comix numbers 9-12, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Gay Comix numbers 13-16, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Gay Comix numbers 17-20, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Gay Comix numbers 21-24, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Gay Comix number 25, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Gay Hearthrobs numbers 1-3, 1976-1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- It Aint Me Babe, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Leonard & Larry, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Mr. Natural numbers 1-3, 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Optic Nerve numbers 1-7, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Radical America Komiks Volume III, number 1, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Real Pulp Comics numbers 1-2, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Slow Death numbers 1-4, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Slow Death numbers 5-8, 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Slow Death numbers 9-11, 1978-1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Super Soul Comix number 1, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Tits & Clits Comix numbers 1-4, 1972-1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Tits & Clits Comix numbers 5-7, 1979-1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Wimmen's Comix numbers 1-4, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Wimmen's Comix numbers 5-8, 1975-1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Wimmen's Comix numbers 9-11, 1975-1983 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Wimmen's Comix numbers 12-14, 1975-1983 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Wimmen's Comix numbers 15-17, 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Young Lust numbers 1-3, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Young Lust numbers 4-6, 1974-1980 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Young Lust numbers 7-8, 1990-1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)